(pensive music)
(vocalist singing in foreign language)
(vocalist continues singing
in foreign language)
(shells clattering)
(vocalist singing in foreign language)
(chains clinking)
(air whooshing)
(fists thudding)
- [Spectator] Come on, boy, get him.
Get down, get your hands up.
(fighters grunting)
- [Spectator] Stop trying to kiss him.
- Down.
- Tackle him.
- Come on.
- Work the liver, boy.
- Righten him up. Come on now.
Get on him.
(hands thudding)
(Mace gasping)
(spectator laughing)
(fist thudding)
(Kojo screaming)
(fighters gasping)
- Get over here on it.
(body thudding)
Get on over here. Come on now.
(fighters gasping)
Get in there. Come on.
Come on now.
(fist thudding)
(Mace screaming)
(bodies thudding)
(fighters gasping and grunting)
(fists thudding)
(Mace screaming)
Get him. Take him.
Finish him.
(fists thudding)
Finish him off.
(hammer thuds)
(brooding music)
(spectators cheering)
(Kojo grunting)
(Mace breathing heavily)
(brooding music continues)
(hammer thuds)
(Master Kenner laughing)
(spectators cheering)
Oh, my God, he's beautiful
when he breaks something.
He did your boy in good, though.
(hands thudding)
(pensive music)
(body rasping)
- [Kojo's Master] How about
another one this evening, hmm?
(hand thuds)
(door clattering)
(footsteps plodding)
(liquid sloshing)
(crickets chirping)
- Ah, like an ox.
Tonight, I got double on you.
So you best get your legs back, son.
Now get.
(hand thuds)
Get through them trees
with them other critters.
(footsteps plodding)
(Elder humming)
Tonight's going to be a big night.
(liquid sloshing)
(Elder continues humming)
(birds chirping)
♪ Ogun, do not reject me ♪
♪ I's walking to Jordan to be free ♪
♪ Oh, freedom ♪
(feet shuffling)
♪ Hallelujah ♪
♪ Coming for to carry me home ♪
(feet shuffling)
(Mace breathing heavily)
- We have lost a son, a brother,
a man whole and true.
He walks with the ancestors now.
He is home.
(water sloshing)
(air whooshing)
(shells clattering)
(pensive music)
(bottle clanking)
(water sloshing)
(hand rasping)
(air whooshing)
(water sloshing)
(Mace breathing heavily)
(birds chirping)
(birds continue chirping)
(feet shuffling)
(air whooshing)
(footsteps plodding)
(birds chirping)
(birds chirping and squawking)
(door clattering)
Ogun,
god of war, protect me.
Olodumare, supreme being,
help me to survive this life.
(footsteps plodding)
(clothes rustling)
(fire rustling)
(crickets chirping)
Oh, I thought the ancestors
had taken ya already.
Come, child, get some warmth.
(clothes rustling)
(floor creaking)
(footsteps plodding)
(crickets chirping)
(fire crackling)
(crickets continue chirping)
Where they snatch you from, child?
- Richmond.
But they done sold me all over.
- You's remember family, child, kinfolk?
- Long time gone now. Just
me, far as I can remember.
(shells clattering)
I've seen those before.
My mom used to pray with
those shells every night.
- Long time ago-
- Mm.
- back in the motherland
before they snatched me,
my village had a grand altar for prayer.
Now, all I got is the dirt,
wood, and these few shells
(hand knocking)
I held tight all these years,
what's left of what we was.
You and this shell ain't much different.
Come. Pray with me, child.
- Mama was always
muttering her hoodoo talk
like it'd change something, but it don't.
I do what I got to.
(hand thuds)
- You's not to blame.
Never was.
Back home, a man like you,
you would've led warriors.
You would've been a god like Ogun.
(hand rasping)
(pensive music)
(shell clattering)
(feet thudding)
(footsteps plodding)
(pensive music continues)
Kojo, that was his name,
a man cut from the same cloth as you.
(fire crackling)
(pensive music continues)
(clothes rustling)
(Mace exhales)
Ogun, do not reject me.
(pensive music continues)
(Mace breathing heavily)
(foot thudding)
(lantern handle squeaking)
(pensive music continues)
Ogun,
god of war, protect him.
Olodumare, supreme being,
help him to survive this life.
Ogun, Ogun, Ogun.
Protect him, protect him, protect him.
Do not reject him.
Do not reject him, reject him.
(pensive music continues)
Ogun, god of war, protect
him, war, protect him.
Olodumare, supreme being,
help him to survive this life,
help him to survive this life.
Ogun, do not reject
him, do not reject him.
Ogun, Ogun, do not reject, reject.
(spectators cheering)
- Come on, come on.
Yeah.
(spectators cheering)
(fist whooshing)
(head thudding)
(hand thuds)
(Mace screaming)
(fists thudding)
(fighters grunting)
(Fred screaming)
(fighters gasping)
(knees thudding)
(spectators cheering)
(fists thudding)
(Mace screaming)
(brooding music)
(hammer thuds)
(fighters gasping)
(pensive music)
(Mace growls)
- Send me home, brother.
(Mace gasping)
(pensive music continues)
(Mace continues gasping)
(fighters gasping)
(gentle music)
(fighters continue gasping)
(gentle music continues)
- What the hell are you doing?
(pensive music)
Break what's left.
(Mace breathing heavily)
(pensive music continues)
(hammer thudding)
- [Spectator] Whoa.
(body thudding)
(Mace breathing heavily)
(Mace continues breathing heavily)
(crickets chirping)
(shells clattering)
(pensive music)
(water sloshing)
(hand rasping)
(crickets chirping)
(Elder exhales)
(crickets and birds chirping)
(crickets and birds continue chirping)
(Elder humming)
(Elder continues humming)
(crickets chirping)
♪ Ogun, do not reject me ♪
♪ I's walking to Joran to be free ♪
♪ Oh, freedom ♪
♪ Hallelujah ♪
♪ Coming for to carry me home ♪
♪ Oh, freedom ♪
♪ Hallelujah ♪
♪ Coming for to carry me home ♪
(crickets chirping)
(crickets continue chirping)
(crickets and birds chirping)
(crickets and birds continue chirping)
(no audio)